RACHEL EMMER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

(262) 366-2208

rachelaemmer@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/rachelaemmer

4666 Raleigh Street Denver, CO 80212

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

Flatiron School Jan 2020-May 2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, PSYCHOLOGY

Colorado State University 2008–2012

TECHNOLOGIES

Ruby

JavaScript

CSS / HTML

Ruby on Rails

React.js

SQL

Node.js

SKILLS

Full Stack Web Development

Software Engineering

Customer Service

Conflict Resolution

Crisis Intervention

Management

Public Speaking

PROFILE SUMMARY

Currently attending Flatiron School in Denver and pursuing a career in Software Engineering. Passionate about exploring, building, creating, and learning. Experienced manager with a demonstrated history of working in the hospitality industry and social services. An advocate for people exhibited by exceptional customer service and supporting at-risk youth and families.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

FLATIRON SCHOOL // DENVER // 2020 - Present

15 Week Intensive Full Stack Web Development, React, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Program.

- Frontend: JS fundamentals(ES6+), Component Pattern, React.js, Redux
- Backend: Ruby fundamentals, MVC pattern, Rails, SQL, ORMs, Active Record, Ruby on Rails

SHIFT MANAGER

SANITAS BREWING // BOULDER // 2015 - 2019

Provided reliable and engaging customer service in a fast paced environment while supporting staff and daily business operations.

- Ensured that each client left with a positive and memorable experience in what is considered, "The Sanitas Journey".
- Attended to daily inquiries and addressed customer issues immediately as they arose.
- Managed daily scheduled staffing, inventory, and ordering of supplies.
- Oversaw the content management system and daily cash flows.
- Assisted with coordinating and event operations.
- Maintained cleanliness, professionalism, and high company standards at all times.

MENTOR

PRN FOR FAMILIES // LAKEWOOD // 2014 - 2018

Provided one on one care and support to clients, including around the clock guidance, support, and crisis management.

- Monitored school attendance and performance, social skills, nutrition, fitness, and overall mental health stability.
- Coordinated with a team of mental health professionals including daily check-ins and weekly reviews.
- Engaged family members in positive activities that resulted in greater unity and positive family dynamics.